# Emma Jayne

## emmajayne0101@gmail.com | (412) 584-9801 | Durham, NC

#### **SUMMARY**

## Front-End Developer

Motivated and intellectually-curious front end developer proficient in React.js, with two years of professional experience in consulting focusing on cloud computing. Demonstrates adaptability and maintains a growth mindset when faced with complex technical challenges.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Publicis Sapient 07/2021 – Present

Associate Software Developer

Los Angeles, CA

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver cloud transformation solutions for clients, including Capital Group and Ford.
- Developed user-friendly and dynamic dashboards using PowerBI, resulting in improved user experience.
- Completed training sequences covering tools like React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, and Azure.
- Promoted from Junior Associate Software Developer in 01/2023.

### **Carnegie Mellon Computing Services**

05/2019 - 05/2021

Student IT Help Desk Assistant

Pittsburgh, PA

- Collaborated with colleagues and customers in-person and via email to troubleshoot issues related to internet connectivity, software downloads, and two-factor authentication.
- Corresponded with customers on behalf of coworkers to help speed up our rate of ticket resolution.

Procter & Gamble 05/2020 – 08/2020

Process Engineering Intern

Auburn, ME

- Improved production efficiency in a factory setting by researching and installing hardware, as well as adjusting machine programming to reduce the number of rejects.
- Performed root cause analysis (RCA) by using machine data in Excel pivot tables to identify pain points throughout the production process and predict how they may be remedied.
- Standardized the organizational system used on the floor for production tools, taking guidance from the 5S organizational system.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Carnegie Mellon University**

08/2018 - 05/2021

B.S., Mechanical Engineering

Pittsburgh, PA

- 3.7/4.0 GPA.
- Social chair (2019) and Vice President (2020) of CMU's chapter of ASME (American Society of Mechanical Engineers).

#### **CERTIFICATIONS, SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Certifications: AZ-900 (10/2022); PL-300 (05/2023)
- Skills: Front-end development; React.js; Redux; JavaScript (ES6+); HTML5; CSS3; Responsive web design; Cross-browser compatibility; Version control (e.g., Git); Webpack; RESTful APIs; User Interface (UI) design; User Experience (UX) design; Debugging and problem-solving; Agile/Scrum methodology; Collaboration and teamwork
- Interests: Hiking; camping; sleeping; reading; crocheting; sewing; music; road trips; foreign languages

Github: https://github.com/ejaynew | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejaynew/ | Digital garden: https://ejaynew.github.jo/